<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Wallace | Astronomer</title>
    <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joshua Wallace | Astronomer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://joshuawallace.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting with Friend About Nonacademic Careers</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/ailei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/ailei/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, a graduate alumna of my department, Ai-Lei Sun, hosted a meeting with graduate students and postdocs in my department, talking about her transition from a postdoc to a nonacademic job. She was visiting campus for reunion weekend and was kind enough to offer to do this. As background for her, she graduated with her Ph.D. two years ago and has been pursuing postdoc work since then. She was sought out by the company Orbital Insight with whom she had had some contact in years past and decided to transition out of academia and work for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Mixture Models and Cluster Membership</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/gaia_gmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/gaia_gmm/</guid>
      <description>In my research, I look for planets around stars in a certain type of star cluster known as a globular cluster. Globular clusters are the oldest known star clusters and are nearly as old as the universe. Although the locations of many of these clusters are well known and documented, interloping stars that happen to be in the same area of the sky as these clusters are always present in telescope images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Shadowing at DataCamp</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/blog/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>The astrophysics academic job application cycle starts soon and my preparations, should I apply for academic jobs, need to start now. Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering one last time whether I want to pursue an academic job before I close that door forever. Just in time for this, I had the opportunity to job shadow at a data science company through Princeton&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ldquo;Take a Ph.D. to Work&amp;rdquo; Program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collisional Fragmentation is Not a Barrier to Close-in Planet Formation</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/collision_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/collision_paper/</guid>
      <description>Article Description The final stage of rocky planet formation involves giant impacts between planet-sized bodies. For planets in regions around where Mercury, Venus, Earth, and Mars are in our solar system, it has previously been shown that such collisions, while epic, are still of sufficiently low velocity to allow for mergers to dominate over fragmentation and thus for planets to be able to form. In this paper, we show analytically that, depending on the exact value of some parameters, this may or may not be the case for regions very close to stars (much closer than Mercury is to the Sun), though the values we think are correct show that planet formation is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acing the Grad School Application</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/ebook/</guid>
      <description>Book&amp;rsquo;s Description You’re ready to apply to graduate school. You’ve worked hard to prepare yourself to realize your dream of being a graduate student, but how can you make sure to produce a winning application that will help you realize this dream? Acing the Grad School Application has everything you need to help you produce the best application possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting the Supernova Breakout Burst in Terrestrial Neutrino Detectors</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/sn_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/sn_paper/</guid>
      <description>Article Description Core-collapse supernovae are profuse emitters of tiny particles called neutrinos. We calculate how well neutrino detectors on Earth would be able to detect a specific feature in the neutrino emission from a nearby supernova, the &amp;ldquo;breakout burst.&amp;rdquo; For this project, I created a Monte Carlo code to simulate detection of the breakout burst across a variety of neutrino detector types and at a variety of supernova distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting the Supernova Breakout Burst in Terrestrial Neutrino Detectors</title>
      <link>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/anisotropy_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshuawallace.github.io/itemized/anisotropy_paper/</guid>
      <description>Article Description For my undergraduate thesis, I investigated how Lyman-alpha emission is affected by and correlated with the environment from which it is emitting. We used a Monte Carlo radiative transfer code and basic prescriptions of anisotropy in a gas cloud&amp;rsquo;s density and/or velocity and then analyzed how these environmental anisotropies affected the emission strength and frequency of the Lyman-alpha photons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>